MICHAEL BALLARD

Software developer

☑ 07969741245☑ mike.ballard@vodafone.com∰ michaelballard.co.uk

github.com/mickybizzle



An ambitious developer with 3 years of experience in a wide range of languages and technologies, with a goal to learn and master front end or full stack development. I am especially keen to persue React and React Native development.

WORK EXPERIENCES

Graduate Techboost Project

Vodafone | December 2019 - Present

- Currently developing a React Native mobile app for new starters at Vodafone.
- Ran workshops for my team to introduce them to mobile app development and React Native.
- Led development for the app and helped members of the team with issues they encountered.
- Took part in UX and UI workshops with senior developers in Vodafone to learn best practice and get feedback from professionals.

Solutions Engineer - IoT

Vodafone | September 2019 -

Present

- Developed IoT solutions for customers using JavaScript on our IoT platform.
- Integrated with 3rd party APIs to expand the capability of our platform.
- Involvement in client workshops to understand requirements and interate projects in an agile manner.
- Ran workshops with the team to introduce them to various technologies such as React Native, Microsoft Flow and Python programming.

Automation Developer - Big Data Platforms & Services

Vodafone | April - September 2019

- Prototyped various machine learning solutions as a POC for reducing manual effort across the Big Data space.
- Developed an intent-analyis algorithm in Python which was used on support tickets to predict with 95% accuracy what department a ticket should be allocated to.
- Aided in development of a Machine Learning model to predict the closure category of tickets.
- Demoed prototypes to senior managers to demostrate the value of automated solutions.

PPMO Coordinator - Vodafone Business

Vodafone I September 2018 - March 2019

- Aided project managers with issues that arose with clients or project teams.
- Developed a reporting dashboard using SAP Business Objects to allow senior managers to get an overview of their project teams and areas of concern.
- Created a website to showcase a new file sharing capability within the department.

Junior Developer

Gloversure | August 2016 - May 2017

- My first professional experience of web and mobile app design.
- Developed a mobile app using the lonic framework for customers to be able to manage their site content from their phone.
- Developed a PHP application to enable the marketting team to create mobile notifications for customers.
- Modernised a lot of legacy code. Most noteably AJAXified the CMS to enable dynamic content and less page redirects.

PROJECTS - CAN BE SEEN ON MY GITHUB, LINKED ABOVE.

React Native animated login UI

Learnt the basics of React Native reanimated animation by creating a sleek login UI with performant animations.

Covid19 Tracker

Developed a web app using React to visualise the spread of coronavirus using the covid19 API.

Sports Team Website

Used React to create a website for a sports team, using various google APIs to pull in scores from a spreadsheet and images/files from a google drive folder.

SKILLS

Technical

JavaScript ES6/TypeScript

ReactJS/React Native

Firebase/AWS Cloud services

Python

PHP

SQL

Professional

Effective communicator

Confident leader

Willingness to help others

Good time management

Other skills

Photography and Filming

Photoshop and Video editing

Good knowledge of PC Hardware

Inevitably acting as tech support for my whole family

EDUCATION

BSc in Computer Science

Aberystwyth University 2014 - 2018

Warwick School

GCSE and A Level 2007-2014

LANGUAGES

English (Native)

INTERESTS

Photography

Mountain biking

Gaming

Anything Elon Musk is doing